Eric Gibbons

CONTACT Information Utah Center for Advanced Imaging Research

University of Utah Cell: (801) 916-2620

729 Arapeen Drive $E\text{-}mail: eric.gibbons@utah.edu}$ Salt Lake City, Utah 84108 $E\text{-}mail: ekgibbons@gmail.com}$

RESEARCH INTERESTS My research interests are in magnetic resonance physics and image formation with the aim of improving the quality of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). This work spans MR physics, biophysics, RF pulse design, image reconstruction algorithms, and clinical implementation, all with the purpose of advancing human health care.

WWW: ekgibbons.github.io

EDUCATION

Stanford University, Stanford, California, USA

Ph.D., Bioengineering, June 2017

• Advisor: John Pauly

• Minor: Electrical Engineering

• Thesis: Robust body diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging

M.S., Bioengineering, June 2013

• Concentration: Medical imaging and signal processing

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA

B.S., Biomedical Engineering, May 2011

• Concentration: Medical imaging and signal processing

• Minor: Mathematics

• Thesis: Correlation-based retrospective concatenation of multi-volume 3D microCT data

Awards

- NIH T32 Cardiovascular Imaging Training Grant, 2017
- ISMRM Educational Stipend Award, 2013, 2014, 2015, 2016
- National Science Foundation Graduate Fellowship, 2012
- Stanford University School of Engineering Dean's Doctoral Diversity Fellowship, 2011
- University of Utah College of Engineering Arel Berrier Scholarship, 2010
- University of Utah Barry M. Goldwater Scholar Nominee, 2010
- University of Utah Presidential Scholarship, 2005 2011
- Member of Tau Beta Pi, 2009 Present
- Eagle Scout, 2003

Positions

Utah Center for Advanced Imaging Research, Salt Lake City, Utah USA

Postdoctoral Fellow.

July 2017 to Present

Working with Dr. Edward DiBella to improve, assess, and apply cardiac MRI techniques. Work includes unique MRI reconstruction algorithms using deep learning techniques, RF pulse design, and improved cardiac diffusion-weighted imaging.

Stanford University, Stanford, California USA

Graduate Research Assistant.

April 2012 to June 2017

Developed a rapid diffusion-weighted MRI sequences for pediatric imaging cases. Pulse sequence development included RF pulse design and reconstruction techniques. This work resulted in a robust protocol that is used routinely at Lucille Packard Children's Hospital at Stanford.

MedWhat, San Francisco, California USA

Consultant/Technical Advisor,

November 2015 to December 2016

Developed novel machine learning algorithms for the purposes of computer vision and natural language processing. In particular, used convolutional neural network algorithms to identify dermatological conditions and developed a robust question-answer system for questions in the medical domain.

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah USA

Edward W. Hsu Research Group

December 2009 to June 2011

Worked to improve dynamic imaging resolution through higher order reconstruction. Developed cross-correlation volumetric stitching algorithm for CT volumes. Ran CT scanner as well as performed image analysis on CT volumes.

Center for Neural Interfaces

December 2008 to November 2009

Developed a neural cuff to hold Utah Slant Electrode Array in place while also providing electrical shielding. Conducted over 60 small animal (Fischer rat) surgeries to implant the device. Monitored post surgery walking behavior, explantation, and perfusions to verify biological response to cuff.

University of Utah Nanofab

July 2008 to August 2009

Specialized on environmental scanning electron microscopy. Characterized biological materials through various surface analysis tools.

Publications

- [1] E. K. Gibbons, J. Mendes, A. S. Chaudhari, and E. V. R. DiBella, "Simultaneous acquisition of 2D SMS and 3D cardiac perfusion MRI volumes using deep learning temporal interpolation," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, in preparation for submission in May 2018.
- [2] E. K. Gibbons, K. K. Hodgson, A. S. Chaudhari, and E. V. R. DiBella, "Multiple diffusion parameter map generation from subsampled q-space imaging using deep learning," *Magnetic Res*onance in Medicine, in preparation for submission in April 2018.
- [3] A. S. Chaudhari, Z. Fang, F. Kogan, J. Wood, K. J. Stevens, E. K. Gibbons, J. H. Lee, G. E. Gold, and B. A. Hargreaves, "Super-resolution musculoskeletal MRI using deep learning," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 2018; doi:10.1002/mrm.27178.
- [4] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Slice profile effects on nCPMG SS-FSE," Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, vol. 79, no. 1, pp. 430–438, 2018.
- [5] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Robust self-calibrating nCPMG aquisition: Application to body diffusion-weighted imaging," *IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging*, vol. 37, no. 1, pp. 200–209, 2018.
- [6] E. K. Gibbons, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body diffusion-weighted imaging using magnetization prepared single-shot fast spin echo and extended parallel imaging signal averaging," *Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 2017; doi:10.1002/mrm.26971.
- [7] E. K. Gibbons, P. Le Roux, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body diffusion weighted imaging using non-CPMG fast spin echo," *IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging*, vol. 36, no. 2, pp. 549–559, 2017.

Conference Proceedings

- [1] E. V. R. DiBella, **E. K. Gibbons**, J. Mendes, Y. Tian, and G. Adluru, "Using artificial intelligence to transform cardiac mri reconstruction methods," in *Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC)*, 2018 Annual International Conference of the IEEE, invited.
- [2] E. K. Gibbons, A. S. Chaudhari, and E. V. DiBella, "Deep slice: expanding cardiac SMS coverage through deep learning slice interpolation," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 26th Annual Meeting, Paris, France, accepted.
- [3] A. S. Chaudhari, Z. Fang, F. Kogan, J. Wood, K. J. Stevens, **E. K. Gibbons**, J. H. Lee, G. E. Gold, and B. A. Hargreaves, "Enhancing MRI resolution and fully-automating tissue segmentation using deep learning," in *Proceedings of the Nvidia GPU Technology Conference* (GTC), San Jose, California, USA, *Best poster award.
- [4] E. K. Gibbons, A. S. Chaudhari, and E. V. R. DiBella, "Expanding SMS coverage in cardiac perfusion MRI through deep learning for temporal interpolation," in *Proceedings of the ISMRM Workshop on Machine Learning, Pacific Grove, California, USA*.
- [5] A. S. Chaudhari, Z. Fang, F. Kogan, J. Wood, K. J. Stevens, E. K. Gibbons, J. H. Lee, G. E. Gold, and B. A. Hargreaves, "Deep-learning-based super-resolution and segmentation for

- clinical and research musculoskeletal MRI," in *Proceedings of the ISMRM Workshop on Machine Learning, Pacific Grove, California, USA*.
- [6] E. K. Gibbons, P. LeRoux, S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Robust nCPMG SS-FSE with accelerated acquisition and reconstruction," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 25th Annual Meeting, Honolulu, Hawaii, 2017, p. 3514.
- [7] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Slice profile effects on non-CPMG SS-FSE acquisitions," in Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, 24rd Annual Meeting, Singapore, Singapore, 2016, p. 1894.
- [8] E. K. Gibbons, S. S. Vasanawala, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Body DWI using nCPMG FSE," in Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, 23rd Annual Meeting, Toronto, Canada, 2015, p. 2540.
- [9] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, and A. B. Kerr, "Single-shot isotropic diffusion weighting with eddy current compensation," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 22nd Annual Meeting, Milan, Italy, 2014, p. 2559.
- [10] E. K. Gibbons, J. M. Pauly, M. Saranathan, B. Rutt, and A. B. Kerr, "A T2-diffusion-prepared cube sequence for brain lesion detection at 7T," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 21st Annual Meeting, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA, 2013, p. 2512.
- [11] E. K. Gibbons, S. J. Holdsworth, M. Aksoy, M. B. Ooi, and R. Bammer, "Analysis of ghosting artifacts for real-time motion correction using EPI," in *Proceedings of International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine*, 20th Annual Meeting, Melbourne, Australia, 2012, p. 3431.
- [12] C. Petty, E. K. Gibbons, R. A. Normann, and G. A. Clark, "Containment for the Utah Slanted Electrode Array," in 5th Annual Mountain West Biomedical Engineering Conference, 2009.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Stanford University, Department of Electrical Engineering, Stanford, California

EE 102A: Signals and Systems

Sophomore and junior level course in continuous- and discrete-time signal and system analysis.

Primary Instructor Summer 2015, Summer 2016 Developed syllabus, created homework, taught lecture, held office hours.

Teaching Assistant, with John Pauly Winter 2013, Winter 2014, Winter 2016 Held office hours, held recitation sessions, lectured occasionally.

EE 369B: Medical Imaging Systems II

Graduate level course on imaging internal structures within the body from a systems viewpoint.

Teaching Assistant, with Dwight Nishimura
Held office hours, held recitation sessions, lectured occasionally.

Spring 2016

EE 369C: Medical Imaging Reconstruction

Graduate level course on medical imaging reconstruction algorithms.

Teaching Assistant, with John Pauly Held office hours, mentored class projects.

Fall 2015

EFS/Lang 688: Writing for Engineering and Science

Class for incoming international graduate students on academic writing, listening, discussion, oral presentation, and spoken usage.

Academic Consultant, with Lisa Quijano

Held office hours, occasionally lectured, consulted on writing projects.

University of Utah, Department of Biomedical Engineering, Salt Lake City, Utah

BIOEN 3900: Biosignals Analysis

Sophomore and junior level course in signal processing and analysis with biomedical applications.

Teaching Assistant, with Edward Hsu Graded, held office hours, held recitation. Spring 2011

Summer 2014

BIOEN 5101: Bioinstrumentation

Junior and senior level course in electronics and signal processing with biomedical applications.

Teaching Assistant, with Edward Hsu

Fall 2009, Fall 2010

Developed an entirely new laboratory component for the course, graded, held office hours, held recitation, lectured occasionally.

Relevant Coursework

Medical imaging systems, convolutional neural networks for visual recognition, introduction to digital communication, medical image reconstruction, RF pulse design for MRI, convex optimization, machine learning, linear dyanmical systems, digital signal processing, mathematics of imaging

Teaching Areas

Introductory circuits courses, signal processing, scientific computing, machine learning, biological physics, and medical imaging systems

TECHNICAL SKILLS Proficient in MRI pulse programming within the Siemens IDEA and General Electric EPIC environ-

LANGUAGES

English, native language

Mandarin Chinese, conversational spoken and basic reading/writing skills

Academic SERVICE

Organizer, University of Utah Department of Radiology Machine Learning Working Group

Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering

Reviewer, International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine

Professional

International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine

Memberships IEEE

Leadership and OUTREACH

Weblos Den Leader

2017-Present

Layton, Utah

Lead and plan scouting activities for 10-year-old Cub Scouts.

Stanford Cycling Club

Ecclesiastical missionary

Boy Scouts of America

2012-2016

Stanford, California Sponsorship officer

Negotiated sponsorship contracts, designed and procured custom team cycling clothing, and helped manage team finances.

Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints

2006-2008

Taichung, Taiwan

Missionary for the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints.

Interests Cycling, skiing, fly fishing, backpacking, analog stereo equipment